Francis Henry Hereford papers, 1877-1929 (bulk 1890-1919)
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
Francis Henry Hereford papers, 1877-1929 (bulk 1890-1919)
AZ 311
Hereford, Francis Henry, 1861-1928
This collection contains correspondence, legal papers, and financial records relating to his law practice, chiefly correspondence between Hereford and the various mining corporations, land and cattle companies he represented. Some correspondence relates to the San Pedro Land Grant.
1.4 linear feet
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections University of Arizona PO Box 210055 Tucson, AZ 85721-0055 Phone: 520-621-6423 Fax: 520-621-9733 URL: http://speccoll.library.arizona.edu/
Restrictions
None.
Biographical Note
Francis Henry Hereford was an attorney in Tucson, Ariz.; he served as Pima County District Attorney from 1882-1895 and was a delegate to the first State Constitutional Convention. Hereford specialized in mining and corporation law and was an attorney for several mining companies in southern Arizona.
Scope and Content Note
This collection contains correspondence, legal papers, and financial records relating to his law practice, chiefly correspondence between Hereford and the various mining corporations, land and cattle companies he represented. Some correspondence relates to the San Pedro Land Grant. Additional material concerns political interests, including correspondence from the Tritle family; family history; and Indian depredation claims involving Solomon Warner, Thomas Gardiner, H.C. Hooker, the Aguirre family, and others. Also included are school enrollment statistics for Tucson schools, 1919; and blueprint maps and newspaper clippings concerning a 1915 widening of 6th Avenue in Tucson.
Hereford, Francis Henry, 1861-1928 -- Archives; Zeckendorf, Louis, 1838-; Vail, Walter L., 1852-1906; Tritle family -- Correspondence; Southern Pacific Company -- Records and correspondence; Baboquivari Land and Cattle Company -- Records and correspondence; San Pedro Cattle Company -- Records and correspondence; Calumet & Arizona Mining Company -- Records and correspondence; New Cornelia Copper Company -- Records and correspondence; Greene Cattle Company -- Records and correspondence; Cañada del Oro Mines -- Records and correspondence; Tucson Mining and Smelting Company -- Records and correspondence; Crittenden Land and Cattle Company -- Records and correspondence; Mammoth-Collins Gold Mines, Ltd. -- Records and correspondence; Mammoth Cyanide Company -- Records and correspondence; Wedge Mining Company -- Records and correspondence; Lawyers -- Arizona; Mines and mineral resources -- Arizona -- History -- Sources; Land titles -- Arizona -- History -- Sources; Indians of North America -- Arizona -- Claims; Strikes and lockouts -- Copper mining -- Arizona; Mining corporations -- Arizona -- History -- Sources; Graham-Tewksbury Feud; San Pedro Land Grant; Schools -- Arizona -- Tucson; Streets -- Arizona -- Tucson; Arizona -- Politics and government -- To 1950; Empire Mine (Santa Cruz County, Ariz.); Rosemont Mine (Pima County, Ariz.); Montana Mine (Santa Cruz County, Ariz.); Correspondence; Bills; Stock certificates
Container List
- Baboquivari Land and Cattle Company, George H. Appel, A. Hemme, M. King. 1895-1916 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Salero Livestock and Land Company, Lucas and Wise, Lazear and Orr. 1897 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- San Pedro Cattle Company, A. N. Schuster, F. C. McKinney, W. H. Dowe. 1890-1895 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- San Pedro Grant. 1895-1897 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Southern Pacific Cases. 1888-1897 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Tewksbury Case. 1893-1894 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Correspondence: General. 1888-1929 (Box 1, Folder 7-9)
- Correspondence: Miscellaneous Mining. 1892-1925 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Legal Correspondence: H. W. Blaisdell land case. 1888-1889 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Legal Correspondence: Walter Vail various cases. 1890-1897 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Legal Correspondence: Joseph Parke murdered at Ft. Huachuca. 1893-1894 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Legal Correspondence: Estate of Charles Myers. 1894-1895 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Legal Correspondence: G. H. Wadleigh land case. 1894-1896 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Legal Correspondence: J. C. Johnson vs. E. N. Fish. 1895-1896 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Legal Correspondence: James Scow regarding price of agricultural products. 1895-1896 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Legal Correspondence: Toppy Johnson regarding property in Phoenix. 1895-1897 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Correspondence: Political. 1888-1925 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Correspondence: Julia R. Charoleau regarding the estate of Paul Rebeil. 1897 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Correspondence: Adeline Hereford. 1902-1922 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Correspondence: Tritle Family. 1895-1926 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Correspondence and tax receipts for Hereford Property. 1888-1897 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Personal bills and receipts. 1888, 1890-1898 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Miscellaneous personal items. (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Bonanza de Cobre Mining Company, Esperanza, Galena and protections claims. 1907-1909, 1913, 1928 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Calumet and Arizona Mining Company and New Cornelia Copper Company. 1905-1919 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Arizona Rare Metals Company. 1914-1919, 1923 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Molybdenum Products Company: Correspondence. 1916-1918 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Molybdenum Products Company: Legal papers. 1916-1917 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Molybdenum Products Company: Stock Book. (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Mammoth-Collins Gold Mines Company: Legal papers. 1899-1902 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Mammoth Cyanide Company. 1899-1903 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Wedge Mining Company: Stock Ledger. 1882-1885 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Greene Cattle Company: Memo of Abstracts of San Pedro Grant, San Rafael del Valle Grant, Babocamari Grant, Brief of Appellant. 1908 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Miscellaneous mining papers. (Box 2, Folder 11)
  Includes:
  Articles of Incorporation of the Reward Mining and Smelting Company, 1892
  Articles of Incorporation of the Virginia Mining and Smelting Company, 1897
  Articles of Incorporation of the Arizona Smelting and Molybdenum Company, 1917
  A mineral patent for a claim in Greaterville Mining District, Pima Co., 1910
  Reports on various mines, etc.
- Canada del Oro Mines, Ltd. and Tucson Mining and Smelting Company, Ltd., J. D. Burgess, Richard Hamilton, F. C. Beckwith, Miltenbert suit. 1892-1897 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Crittenden Land and Cattle Company, R. R. Richardson. 1892-1897, 1916-1919 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Empire Mine. 1889-1897 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Gunsight Mining and Milling Company, C. G. Deatherage. 1895-1896 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Montana Mine, Louise Zeckendorf. 1889-1917 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Rosemont Copper Mines, George L. Thompson, Lewisohn Bros. 1896-1897 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Indian Claims Cases. 1888-1898 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  Includes Solomon Warner, Thomas Gardiner, Aguirre family, H. C. Hooker, and others. Claims for Indian depredations.
- Tucson Public Schools: Miscellaneous material. 1919 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Tucson 6th Avenue Widening. 1915 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Manuscript on Mining Laws. (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Miscellaneous items. (Box 3, Folder 11)
  Includes
  Francis H. Hereford Tax Titles
  Scrip Book 2
  Miscellaneous items on the Colorado River
  Document on the settlement of the Ls Osa Cattle Company, 1913
  Unidentified fragments on a financial transaction
- Benjamin H. Hereford: Certificate as Attorney of the Supreme Court of the Territory of Arizona. Signed by Joseph Neugass, Clerk of the Supreme Court, A. T. January 3, 1877 (Box 4)
- Benjamin H. Hereford: Certificate of appointment as Notary Public of Pima County. Signed by J. C. Fremont, Governor of Territory of Arizona. March 7, 1881 (Box 4)
- Benjamin H. Hereford: Certificate of election as District Attorney of Pima County. Signed by William J. Osborn, Clerk of Pima County Board of Supervisors. November 17, 1884 (Box 4)
- Frank H. Hereford: Certificate to practice in the Supreme Court and other courts of the Territory of Arizona. Signed by E. H. Cook for E. B. Dodge, Clerk of the Supreme Court, A. T. July 8, 1886 (Box 4)
- Frank H. Hereford: Certificate of election as delegate to the Constitutional Convention of Arizona, representing Pima County. Signed by N. O. Murphy, Secretary of Arizona. June 18, 1891 (Box 4)
- Frank H. Hereford: Certificate as Attorney and Counsellor of the U. S. Supreme Court. Signed by James H. McKenney, Clerk of the U. S. Supreme Court. March 1, 1907 (Box 4)
- Frank H. Hereford: Certificate to practice in the Supreme Court and other courts of the Territory of Arizona. Signed by C. F. Leonard, Clerk of the Supreme Court, Arizona. January 24, 1914 (Box 4)
- Frank H. Hereford: Certificate as proctor, advocate, attorney, solicitor and counsellor of the U. S. District Court, in and for the southern district of California. Signed by T. F. Green for William. M. Van Dyke, Clerk of the Court. December 14, 1917 (Box 4)